

## Profile

Experienced fullstack Engineer as well as instructor with over 11 years of experience in enterprise and consulting industries. My professional journey is nurtured in web development, building technical expertise leveraging agile and devOps practices, mentoring teams, managing resources, and working with diverse teams across the globe.

# Employment History

Senior .Net Consultant - Technology at Revature, Arlington Texas July 2019 — Present

- Created Enterprise web apps leveraging C#, .Net Core, Asp.Net core, Sql Server/PostgresSql, EFCore (Code-First), Angular-, TypeScript.
- Leveraged Agile methodology (SCRUM) with Azure DevOps for CI/CD pipeline, SonarCloud for code quality and Git for source Control. Documentation and diagramming the application process.
- · Integrating external RESTful api using Httpclient and JSON.
- Developing and designing enterprise automation using UiPath
  Studio and manage deployment using UiPath Orchestrator. Also used Hyperautomation Automation Hub and Task Capture.
- Auditing delivery, code reviewing, monitoring performance, approving time-sheets of associates.
- Conducting panel interviews and selecting associates based on the readiness for client projects.

#### Lead Engineer at HCL Technologies, Noida

October 2016 — September 2018

- Development and enhancement of backend applications using
  .Net Framework and Azure for Denmark based client-Vestas.
- Most of the applications were intranet based web app developed in Asp.Net WebAPI, MVC5, SQL Server 2012, Entity Framework 4, AngularJs, TypeScript.
- Developing middlewares to integrate SAP applications with Databases.
- Creating users stories, reviewing and assigning tasks to subordinates.
- Worked in a team environment practicing SCRUM and DevOps.

# Web Developer at GC Web Venture Pvt. Ltd (aka IndiaLends ), New Delhi

April 2016 — October 2016

 Worked with a fin-tech based startup, where I learned to use finance APIs for analytics and providing solutions for B2C or B2B products.

#### **Details**

India: +91-9027445197, UK: +44-7732-750-202 pushp.com@gmail.com

#### **Skills**

C#.NET

T-SQL

**Entity Framework Core** 

ASP.NET Core

ASP.NET MVC

ASP.NET Web API

SOA, SOAP, WCF, RESTful

HTML5/CSS/JavaScript

Angular and TypeScript

Azure DevOps, CI/CD

Microsoft Azure PaaS

Microservices, Docker

Git, TFS, VSTS, Gitlab

**Robotic Process Automation** 

**UiPath Studio** 

**UiPath Orchestrator** 

Hyperautomation

#### **Hobbies**

traveling, cooking and reading

#### Languages

English

Hindi

Punjabi

#### Links

LinkedIn

- Developed a pilot project *Employee Verification System* to check employee's credibility based on credit score and social score.
- Integrating 3rd party APIs (Experian, Hello Soda).
- Working closely with the product manager, analytics team and stakeholders to map the requirements into a solution using .Net related technologies.
- Part of my role also involved working on the enhancement of B2C products.

## Consultant at Koenig Solutions Ltd , New Delhi

December 2014 — May 2016

- Understanding client's technical requirement and delivering user stories accordingly.
- Deliverable are created using Microsoft .Net framework, Azure
  PaaS services and Sql Server.
- Developing web apps using **Asp.Net MVC4**, **Entity Framework 4** as middleware leveraging DbFirst approach.
- Connecting web services using Azure Service Bus and configuring Azure Storage for storing multimedia.

# Developer and trainer at ATS Infotech Pvt Ltd., New Delhi

April 2013 — October 2014

- Developing in-house application using .Net Framework 2.0, C# and Asp.Net web forms, Sql Server 2008.
- Creating custom asp.net controls.
- Connecting backend with server-side code using ADO.Net.
- Created SOAP Service leveraging WCF and web Services (asmx), configuring endpoints and understanding WSDL.

## Education

# Bachelor of Technologies (Computer Science Engineering), Neelkanth Institute of Technology, Meerut

August 2008 — June 2012

- Leading cultural fests and events.
- Winner in group discussions, extempore intra-college competitions.

## Certification

#### **Microsoft Certified Trainer**

May 2015 — Present

Microsoft

## MCSD: App Builder — Certified 2016

July 2016 — Present

Microsoft

#### Certified RPA developer

March 2019 — Present

UiPath